newearth.com 2018-01-11

# Privacy Policy | New Earth - Life Starts Here. Living Begins Now.

## Our Commitment To Privacy

Thank you for visiting www.newearth.com or an authorized replicated site www.teamnewearth.com (the "Site"). Your privacy is very important to us at New Earth, and we are committed to protecting and safeguarding your privacy. It is our policy to keep your personal information confidential. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. Please take a moment to read the following Policy to learn how we handle your personal information.

New Earth does not collect Personal Information about individuals who visit our site except when the information is specifically provided on a voluntary basis. 

### Information We Collect 

We may collect Personal Information (including name, address, telephone number, email address and, when necessary, credit card information) when you: 

  * Place an order from our Web site
  * Return an item or make an exchange
  * Inquire about our products and services

In addition, you may voluntarily provide Personal Information (such as name, address, email address, and telephone number) to be forwarded to an New Earth Independent Associate for the purpose of contacting you with details regarding the New Earth opportunity, including contact by email. In this case, we will keep a record of the contact, including the Personal Information, in your New Earth file. We use this information to provide better service in the event that you contact us again.

### **New Earth Independent Associate (Associate)**

When you decide to become an authorized New Earth Associate, or when you register to shop online as a Preferred Customer, we will collect Personal Information (such as name, address, email address, and telephone number). This Personal Information is securely stored in your New Earth contact file. You will be assigned an identification number and you will select a password which will be necessary to gain entrance to the website and to access your Personal Information. 

We may also collect non-personally identifiable information from you when you visit the Site (e.g., your IP address, browser type, domain name, etc.). This information is collected and analyzed in the aggregate in order to improve the function and content of the Site.

### **Use of Information**

Personal Information will not be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties without the approval of the website user at the time of collection. The user will have the opportunity to indicate whether he or she would like to "opt out" of receiving promotional and/or marketing information about other products, services and offerings from New Earth and/or any third parties. Further, notwithstanding any "opt out" of promotional information by the user, New Earth reserves the right to contact a customer or Associate regarding account status, changes to the Associate Agreement and other matters relevant to the underlying service and/or the information collected.

We use the information that is collected about you for a variety of purposes, such as confirming and fulfilling orders, adding you to our e-mail subscription list, providing your name to a New Earth Associate in connection with potential interest in New Earth products or the business opportunity. We also use the information in analyzing trends and statistics, enhancing the operation of the website.

From time to time you may voluntarily provide Personal Information to complete questionnaires or to participate in contests, polls or personalized assessments. We use this information to improve our products and services. We may also use your Personal Information to provide you newsletters and other marketing information we think would be of particular interest to you concerning things such as new products or website features. But you always have the opportunity to let us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited promotional materials from us, and we will make every reasonable effort to honor such requests.

Your mentoring sales organization acts as a support network, providing advice, assistance and information to assist you in building and maintaining a successful New Earth business. Therefore, New Earth will share Personal Information with your upline sales organization. They have agreed that such information is confidential, and not to share your information with any non-affiliated third parties, and are obligated to observe the intent of this Privacy Policy. 

We may share Personal Information you provide online with other New Earth-affiliated entities and/or trusted business partners with whom we collaborate. We may develop business relationships in the future with business partners. In these instances, we may share or otherwise allow access to information that is collected about you that will enable our business partners to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest. We may employ third party vendors to perform functions on our behalf. Examples may include delivering packages, fulfilling orders, e-mail administrative functions, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These vendors will be under bound by contract to use confidential data only for those purposes for which they are hired. 

New Earth may disclose Personal Information to a third party in the event that New Earth sells all or part of its assets to such third party or merges with or is acquired by the third party.

We may disclose the information that we collect about you when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities that may be causing injury to you, to us or to others. At times we may be required by law or legal process to disclose your personal information, and we may also disclose information when we believe the law requires it. We may also disclose information about you if we believe that disclosure is necessary for the public interest. 

Users may always "opt out" of further promotional contacts at any time. Also, upon request, New Earth will take reasonable efforts to delete a user's personal information from its database. It may be impossible to delete a user's entry without some residual information because of backups and records of deletions.

If you are visiting the Website from outside the United States and provide New Earth with personal information, please note that your personal information will be transferred, stored and processed within the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may not be as comprehensive as those in your country. _By doing business or interacting with New Earth, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information to facilities located in the United States and other facility locations selected by New Earth and to the application of United States law regarding the collection, transfer and maintenance of your personal information._

### **Special note for residents of California**

Under California Civil Code § 1798.83, we are required to disclose to consumers the following information upon written request: (1) the categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties within the prior year, if that information was subsequently used for marketing purposes; and (2) the names and addresses of all such third parties to whom such the personal information was disclosed. We hereby disclose that we have not disclosed any such personal information regarding any California resident during the one-year period prior to the effective date of this Privacy and Information Security Policy. California residents seeking additional information on this requirement or our privacy practices in general may write to us at [support@newearthsupport.com](mailto:support@newearthsupport.com), with the headline “PRIVACY REQUEST” in the message line. They may also send paper mail to:

New Earth Company  
PO Box 609  
565 Century Court  
Klamath Falls, OR 97601

Please write "Attention: PRIVACY" in the address.

### **Cookies**

Like many websites, the New Earth website uses “cookie” technology. A "cookie" is a small data file transferred to your computer's hard drive that allows a website to respond to you as an individual, gathering and remembering information about your preferences. When you first connect to our site, the cookie identifies your browser with a unique, random number. The cookies we use do not reveal any personal information about you, except perhaps your first name so we can welcome you on your next visit. Cookies help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how long they spend there. We use cookies to study traffic patterns on our site so we can make the site even better.

### **Data Security**

It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure and while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee or warrant complete security. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of data. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract to only what they need to carry out their responsibilities. When you make a purchase on our Web site, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. 

Every user that has an account on the Website is responsible for (i) keeping his or her account password confidential and secured, (ii) avoiding unauthorized access to his or her computer; and (iii) keeping the e-mail address associated with that account current (you acknowledge that it is important to keep the e-mail address associated with that account current because although you may be able to log into your New Earth account using an old e-mail address, you will not receive messages from New Earth about your orders and inquiries or other matters).

You shall be responsible for protecting the confidentiality of your password(s). You acknowledge that, although the Internet is often a secure environment, sometimes there are interruptions in service or events that are beyond the control of New Earth, and New Earth shall not be responsible for any data lost while transmitting or receiving information on the Internet.

### **Third Party Websites**

The Site may provide hyperlinks, which are highlighted words or pictures within a hypertext document that, when clicked, take you to another place within the document, to another document altogether, or to other web sites not controlled by New Earth. These hyperlinked web sites may contain privacy provisions that are different from those provided herein. New Earth is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of information collected through these web sites or links, and New Earth expressly disclaims any and all liability related to such collection, use, or disclosure.

### **Protection of Children's Privacy**

The Site is a general audience web site that is not specifically designed or targeted at children. If you are under 18, you may use the Site only with involvement of a parent or guardian. We abide by the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and other relevant laws. We do not knowingly collect, use or disseminate any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If, however, we become aware that personally identifiable information regarding a child under the age of 13 has been collected at the Site, we will delete such information from our records. 

### **How to Access or Correct Your Information**

If you identify any inaccuracy in your personal information, or you need to make a change or would like to verify such information, please contact us so that we may update our records or you may go online to New Earth's web site and update your own information. New Earth contact information is set forth below. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to accommodate all such requests.

### **Modifications to Policy**

The foregoing policies are effective as of July 25, 2013. New Earth reserves the right to change this policy at any time and will notify users of the existence of a new Privacy Policy via e-mail or by posting the latest version on our Site. Any changes to this Policy will be effective immediately upon notice. Use of the Site after notice of changes will be deemed acceptance of such changes. Be sure to review this Privacy Policy periodically to ensure that you are familiar with the most current version. This statement and the policies outlined here are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any concerns about our use of your information or about this Privacy Policy, please send mail to:

New Earth Company  
PO Box 609  
Klamath Falls, OR 97601

Or, send an email to [support@newearthsupport.com](mailto:support@newearthsupport.com), or call (800)-800-1300. We will make every reasonable effort to address your concerns and remedy any problems you bring to our attention.
